Ethan Lindsey

(515)-619-8081 | ethandev.net | ethan.james.lindsey@gmail.com | LinkedIn: ejlindseycs | GitHub: Ethan[Lindsey

Summary

Recent university graduate with success in software analysis and design. Experience tutoring undergraduate computer science courses to help students build their software development skills. Comfortable with learning new technologies quickly, including most recently creating a portfolio website using React and AWS.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Music Technology

Iowa State University - GPA: 3.91

Experience

Computer Science Tutor

January 2022-December 2022

Iowa State University, Communications Building

Ames, IA

- Tutored over 100 clients total with an average of 4 clients per hour.
- Successfully addressed over 500 errors with a 96% success rate.
- Collaborated with more than 10 other tutors to solve complex problems.
- Applied solid understanding data structures, algorithms, and design.

Exam Proctor

August 2021–December 2021

Iowa State University, Exam Accommodations Center

Ames, IA

- Administered exams for up to 30 students at any given time.
- Monitored security cameras and enforced strict policies to ensure integrity.
- Managed assistive technology to address physical and mental disabilities.

Software Projects

Portfolio Website

Tuly 2023-Present

- Wrote 24.3 KB of JavaScript and CSS for React frontend.
- Frontend sends data to AWS Dynamo DB using CRUD operations.
- AWS Lambda triggers and Simple Email Service used to send notifications.

Anthill

August 2022–December 2022

- Senior design team project using Agile development process and Jira.
- Conducted professional presentations of our progress monthly to our client.
- Contributed over 60% of the final code and designed our database schema.
- Reviewed all peer code and fixed a critical security flaw that risked all user data.

Web Adventure

July 2022

- 2D web-based game made using JavaScript, Kotlin, Spring Boot, and MySQL.
- Created class structure for animation to increase efficiency and simplicity.
- User authentication using Spring Security and password encryption.

Technical Skills

Languages

Proficient

C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Python, MySQL

Familiar

December 2022 Dart, Kotlin, PHP, C#

Technologies

AWS, React, NumPy, Spring Boot, Firebase, Flutter, Node.js

Software

Excel, Docker, Android Studio

Soft Skills

Critical Analysis **Conflict Resolution Active Learning** Adaptability

Awards

ISU Dean's List

December 2019-December 2022

Highest 2% LAS Freshman

May 2020

Highest 2% LAS Junior

May 2021

Relevant Topics

Algorithm Design **Data Structures Computational Geometry Network Protocols Network Security**